mail.com 2009-06-20

# mail.com

**mail.com's Privacy Policy**  
**Effective: April 1, 2009**

* * *

Mail.com Media Corporation ("Mail.com") is committed to protecting your privacy and maintaining a safe online experience for all of our users and customers while providing a quality user experience. Because we gather certain types of information about and from you, our users and customers, in order to fulfill your requests and better serve your needs, you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of this information. This Privacy Policy discloses what information we gather, how we use it, how to correct or change it, and what steps we take to safeguard personal information provided to us both online and offline. Please read the complete Privacy Policy below, as well as our User Agreement, and contact us if you have any questions.

When you **register** for an account:

| **_We Will:_** |   | **_We Won't:_**  
---|---|---  
  
1\. Collect personally identifiable (e.g. name, address) and demographic(e.g. age, gender) information about you. We will use the non-personally identifiable demographic data to serve ads (pertaining to your geographic location, age, or gender) on our Web site when you log in. The information is collected when you register for your e-mail account.

2\. Provide industry-standard security to protect your personal information while it is in our possession. If you use your credit card to pay for premium services, then your credit card information will be encrypted using SSL technology and will be stored on secure servers.

3\. Give you access to review and edit your personal and demographic information while it is in our possession.

4\. Send you service announcements notifying you of any new products or updates to the service. We may use your alternate e-mail address and home address to ensure that you receive important information about your account or information you have requested. If you do not wish to receive these announcements simply go to the bottom of the newsletter and follow the instructions to make sure you do not receive any further notifications.

5\. Send you monthly newsletters that highlight certain e-mail features and provide you with information about additional products and services we think might be of interest to you. We will provide you with the opportunity to "opt out" of the newsletter, beginning with the initial newsletter.

6\. Give you the choice of "opting in" to receive third party mailings.

7\. Make it easy for you to unsubscribe from any mail.com-owned mailing list by following directions at the bottom of any e-mail that you receive from us (unless it is vital to the operation of your account)

8\. Bundle information to better design our Web site and to share with our advertisers and partners. This aggregate information will not be used to learn anything about any particular individual.

9\. In developing our business, we may engage in the sale of certain assets and the company itself, or parts of it, may be sold, merged or otherwise transferred. In such transactions and changes in ownership, user information, whether personally identifiable or otherwise, may constitute one of the transferred assets. Mail.com will notify affected users in accordance with the procedure for changing this Privacy Policy described below.

|   | 

1\. Send you unsolicited commercial e-mail (spam).

2\. Do the following, without your explicit permission;

  1. i. Give anyone access to your e-mail or open or read messages in your account, unless such release is necessary to:

a. Satisfy any law, regulation, or legal request. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.  
b. Conduct investigations of consumer complaints and possible breaches of law;  
c. Enforce or apply the terms of our user agreement, or d. Protect the rights, property, or safety of Mail.com, our users, or the public.

3\. Share any data with outside parties that would identify a specific user (except in those circumstances listed in 2(i) above).

4\. Knowingly collect any information from children under the age of 13. To find out more about the Children.s Online Privacy Protection Rule [Click here](http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm)

5\. Contact you via e-mail or any other method to ask you for your password. Do not share your password with anyone; you should only enter it directly into our Web site.

6\. Contact you via e-mail or any other method to ask you for your credit card information. You should only enter this information directly into our Web site.

7\. Materially change how we use your personally identifiable information without placing a prominent notice on our Web site first.

**_Tell-A-Friend_** : If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend.s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Mail.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

Your friend may contact us at [onlinehelp@staff.mail.com](mailto:onlinehelp@staff.mail.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

**_Cookies_** : Our Web site uses cookies for the purpose of identifying you when you access your account. This allows us to pre-populate your E-mail address on the login page and to distinguish between your Web session and that of the many other people using our service and allow us to offer other functionalities (such as screening for age and "recognizing" you to speed up your log-in when you visit our Web site). We may also automatically collect your IP and referring Web site addresses, browser type, domain name and Web site access times (as described below). Our web-based mail service will not function unless your browser is set to accept cookies. You can turn off cookies, but that will affect your online experience.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers or ad-servers) use cookies on our Web site to track the effectiveness of when they serve ads by collecting non-personally identifiable information . We have no access to or control over these cookies once set on our site. For information on how to opt-out of Ad serving cookies go to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>

**_Links_** : Be aware that when you click on ad banners, you may be redirected to other sites not operated by Mail.com. You are responsible for information that you provide to these sites. We recommend that you review the privacy policy of any site that requests personal information. Note that this policy does not cover the privacy practices of these linked sites.

**_General Information Collected_** : When visiting our site, some general information is collected including: IP address (your computer's unique signature) Operating system (e.g., Windows 95) Browser software (e.g., Microsoft Internet Explorer, Netscape) Internet Service Provider (e.g., Earthlink, Verizon).

The information we collect is aggregated to reflect the population as a whole rather than focused on individuals. We use it to help us better understand the people who visit our Web site and to continually improve our products and services. In addition, like many other sites with paid advertising, we disclose some of this non- personally identifiable, aggregate information to advertisers to inform them of the number of people who have seen and clicked on their advertisements.

**_Third Party Service Providers_** : Agents and affiliates of Mail.com may occasionally process individual user data as required to provide services for which the user has registered. However, they are not allowed to use this information for any other purpose. All individual user data is owned and controlled by Mail.com. Features on the Web site that utilize third party service providers include: e-mail notification services and credit card processing. As in any transaction, your credit card company will have all relevant information about the name of the vendor, item(s) purchased, date, total cost and other information necessary to process the transaction. We will not otherwise provide any personal data to your credit card company without your permission.

From time to time we partner with third party service providers to offer additional products and services within the Web site. To participate in these offerings, you may be asked to provide personal information and agree to terms and conditions relating to the third party service provider. Such requests for information will be displayed and requested by the third party in a straightforward manner with explanation as to whose privacy statement governs the collection of such information. These services include: dating and personals, employment services, home loans, apartment rentals and other services, all of which are purely optional for the user.

**_Personal Information_** : It is the responsibility of each user to provide Mail.com with accurate information at all times. Personal information collected during the account registration process includes: name, street address, city, state, zip code, country, age, gender as well as an alternate email address (optional). Payment information will also be collected if users have registered for a premium account. In order to update the personal information, users may do the following::

  * Login to the account via the website
  * On the top navigation bar click on "My Account"
  * Make any changes and then click “"Finish”" to save the changes

**_Changes to our Privacy Policy_** : We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy as necessary to protect our users and to comply with best practices employed by other publishers and regulatory organizations across the industry.. We recommend that you check the Privacy Policy when you visit our Web site to be sure that you are aware of and understand our current policy. If we make material changes to this policy, or in how we use or collect your personally identifiable information, we will prominently post such changes prior to implementing the change. We will not make any retroactive material changes in how we handle previously collected personal information unless you allow us to do so, or unless we are legally required to do so, and in such a case we will e-mail registered Web site visitors information on material changes to this Privacy Policy. 

**_Your California Privacy Rights_** : Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice describing what categories of personal customer information Mail.com shares with third parties or corporate affiliates for those third parties or corporate affiliates' direct marketing purposes. That notice will identify the categories of information shared and will include a list of the third parties and affiliates with which it was shared, along with their names and addresses. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address: Mail.com, 9800 South La Cienega Blvd., Los Angeles, CA 90301. In your request, please specify that you want a "Your Mail.com California Privacy Rights Notice". Please allow at least 30 days for a response. 

**Questions?**

For any questions or comments concerning Mail.com's privacy policy, please write to: [PrivacyDirector@mail.com](mailto:privacydirector@mail.com)

Or send a letter to:  
9800 South La Cienega Blvd.  
Los Angeles, CA 90301  
(310) 321-5000

Law Enforcement inquiries can be directed to [LegalCompliance@corp.mail.com](mailto:LegalCompliance@corp.mail.com).

All spam, UCE and general abuse issues should be directed to: [abuse@mail.com](mailto:abuse@mail.com).

For general problems with your account, please [click here](http://mail01.mail.com/templates/common/us/contactUsExt.htm).  
  
© Copyright 2009 mail.com All rights reserved.
